[{"question":"Power factor can be improved by connecting which among these -","answers":{"a":"Static capacitor","b":"Resistors","c":"Synchronous Condensers","d":"A & C both"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"To reduce the power consumption, the capacitors should be located -","answers":{"a":"As close as possible too load","b":"As far as to the load","c":"Not too close not too far from the load","d":"All of these"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"If power factor is less than unity it will result in -","answers":{"a":"Large kVA rating of equipment","b":"Greater conductor size","c":"Large copper losses","d":"All of these"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"If load current decrease then power factor -","answers":{"a":"Will also decrease","b":"Will increase","c":"Will remain unchanged","d":"None of these"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"A pure inductive load draws -","answers":{"a":"Leading reactive power","b":" Active power","c":"Lagging reactive power","d":" None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Active power is equal to -","answers":{"a":"VIcosΦ","b":"VIsinΦ","c":"VI","d":"Any of these above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"Wattless component is -","answers":{"a":"I","b":"IsinΦ","c":"IcosΦ","d":"None of these"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"In order to improve the power factor of equipment operating at lagging power factor, a capacitor is connected -","answers":{"a":"In series with the equipment","b":"In parallel with the load","c":"In series-parallel with the load","d":"Either A & B"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"What is the advantage of the static capacitors-","answers":{"a":"Low losses","b":"Easy installation","c":"Lower maintenance","d":"All of the above"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"Which of the following is present inside the fluorescent tube -","answers":{"a":"Helium and oxygen","b":"Argon and carbon dioxide","c":"Argon and neon","d":"Mercury vapour"},"correctAnswer":"d"}]

